grahamcluley.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy policy | Graham Cluley

## Your privacy is important to us

Cluley Associates, the owners of grahamcluley.com, believes that the privacy of our website visitors is extremely important. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected by our website and how it is used.

This privacy policy sets out how grahamcluley.com collects, uses, and protects any information that you either explicitly or automatically send when using this website.

## Our attitude to your personal data

Cluley Associates does not sell, trade, or transfer your personally identifiable information to third-parties. For general web browsing no personal information is revealed to us.

Apart from information that you volunteer to Cluley Associates either by [emailing us](https://www.grahamcluley.com/contact/) or by filling out a form e.g. registering for our newsletter, Cluley Associates does not collect any personal data about you on this website.

If you send us an email, we may collect your name, your email address, and any other information which you choose to give us. Any information that you provide is used by Cluley Associates solely for the purposes for which it is provided. If we do collect any personal data, it will be processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reasons for which it was first collected. We will comply with our obligations and safeguard your rights under the GDPR at all times.

## What this site collects, and what we do with the collected data

We will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your consent. Any personal information which you volunteer to us will be treated with the highest standards of data security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

For the most part this site is read-only, however there are a number of functions that can and do collect information as a function of what they are. These include:

  * **Cookies Data** : Regular use of the internet involves the sending and receiving of cookie data, and this is true for this site as well. No special attempt to harvest cookie data is being made on this site, and no attempt is ever made to correlate visitor data with real people or identities. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites or the [About Cookies website](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).
  * **IP Data**: Another natural part of Internet use is the sending of internet protocol (IP) addresses to the destination server, in this case grahamcluley.com. Just as with cookie data, no attempt is ever made to link source IP addresses to any information that is personally identifiable.
  * **Ads** : Good news - we hate ads as much as you do. This website use a sponsorship rather than an ad model, so there is no unpleasant script running anywhere on the website. The sponsorship link is just a regular link at the top of each webpage, and is also found occasionally in sponsored posts.

Access to the site is logged in a standard fashion using the web server logs. These logs may contain cookie and IP address data, as is standard with most web log formats.

Access to this server is restricted to very few people, and log data has never been requested - nor provided to - any third party. The main web server is hosted with [Pressidium](https://pressidium.com/legal/privacy-policy/), a managed WordPress hosting company. An additional web server, used for management of the newsletter, is hosted with [DigitalOcean](https://www.digitalocean.com/legal/privacy/).

No log data will ever be used to attempt to link cookies or IP addresses to actual people, and this log data will never be provided to third parties, unless obliged to do so by a rule of law.

## Site Security

While it’s not possible to guarantee this website’s security, a great number of measures have been taken to ensure that this server cannot be penetrated without authorization. These include the use of limited accounts, regular security updates, and the use of hardened remote access options such as multi-factor authentication.

## Third Party Functionality and Privacy Policies

This is a non-exclusive list of the key third parties that this website has a relationship with:

  * **Amazon** :  
[Amazon Simple Email Service (SES)](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) is a service provider for this site, assisting in the sending of emails to users who have subscribed to the site’s GCHQ newsletter. [ [AWS Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) ]
  * **Google Analytics** :  
[Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/) provides web traffic analytics for this site. [ [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) ]
  * **Automattic** :  
[Automattic](https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/) provides web traffic analytics for this site, and helps keep spam under control by filtering out spam comments. [[Automattic Privacy Notice](https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/) ]

## Contact

We take these issues extremely seriously, and if you have any concerns about how your data is being treated, or would like to report an incident, please use the following email address:
